

Humberto Yusta Gómez

humbertoyusta02@gmail.com

 $+53\ 55743975$

Dirección Calle Maceo #20 Zulueta, Remedios Villa Clara, Cuba

> GitHub humbertoyusta

LinkedIn humberto-yusta-036710212

Humberto Yusta Gómez

Estudiante, Programador Competitivo

About Me Graduado de preuniversitario con cinco años de experiencia en programación competitiva. Apasionado por las Matemáticas y las Ciencias de la Computación, dedicado al aprendizaje continuo, desarrollo profesional y dispuesto a aprender nuevas tecnologías y herramientas si surge la necesidad.

Experience

2018 - Presente, Programador Competitivo

Resultados destacados:

- Bronze medal at the International Olympiad in Informatics (IOI 2020) and best Latin-American score.
- Master at codeforces.com, Yellow coder at atcoder.jp, Platinum division at usaco.org
- Gold medal (3rd place), Bronze medal, and Silver medal at the Ibero-American Competition in Informatics(CIIC) 2020, 2019 and 2018 respectively.
- 3rd place at the 2020 ICPC Caribbean Finals (Qualifier), 6th place at 2019 ICPC Caribbean Finals. Participated as guest in both.
- Gold medal at the Cuban Informatics Olympiad in 2020, 2019 and 2018. 1st, 2nd and 13th place respectively.
- 8th place at the Asia-Pacific Informatics Olympiad 2021 Open Contest.

2021 - Present, Problem Setter & Trainer

Volunteer Work

- Author of Codeforces Round #768 (Div. 1, Div. 2), a competitive programming contest with more than 26000 participants.
- Problem setter, tester and staff member in the following contests:
 - Ibero-American Competition in Informatics (CIIC) 2022
 - Ibero-American Competition in Informatics (CIIC) 2021
 - Cuban Olympiad in Informatics 2022
 - Cuban Team Selection Contests for the Ibero-American Competition in Informatics in 2021
- Author of three educational blogs on codeforces: "XOR Hashing.", "K-th smallest edge on a tree's path, a tutorial about its approaches" and "Dp with connected components, a simple way to understand it.".
- Personally trained the IOI 2021 Cuba Team for two weeks.

Education

Sep. 2017 - Aug. 2020, IPVCE Ernesto Che Guevara

High School Graduate

Awarded as one of the best graduates of the Knowledge Contest Training Center.

Programming Skills

Programming Languages

○ C++ ○ Java ○ Typescript ○ Python

Development Software

Git
NestJS
PostgreSQL
Polygon